A Guide to the Donald R. Griffin papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA164
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Projects, 2
  - Chillagoe Expedition (Box 15, Folder 148)
    bats; bowerbirds; Peter Dwyer; Leslie Hall; Jim Simmons; Dermot Smyth; Rod A. Suthers; David Thompson; Cliff and Dawn Frith Prionodura; Indiana University; National Science Foundation
  - Huyck Preserve (Box 15, Folder 149)
    Cornell University; Harvard University; New York Division of Fish and Game; Bradbury, Bump, Dalgleish; Lincoln Pond; G. E. Folk; William Hamilton, Jr.; Thomas Ordway, M.D.; see also Projects-Bat Banding
  - Panama (Box 15, Folder 150)
    bat acoustics; Prentice Bloedel (?Pen?); John H. Hughes; Al Novick; Harold Trapido; William Wimsatt; Canal Zone Corrosion Laboratory; Empire Devices; Gorgas Memorial Laboratory; Office of Naval Research; U.S. Public Health Service
  - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (Box 15, Folder 151)
    bats; birds; dolphins; whales; Bronx Zoo; Millbrook; New York Blood Center; Office of Naval Research; Randolph Air Force Base; Richard Backus; Andrew Bunker; Helen Clark; Cameron Gifford; Judith Grassle; Brackett Hersey; A. J. Kalmijn; John Kanwisher; Ron Larkin; Elizabeth Redfield Marsh; John M. Teal; Jose and Susi Torre-Bueno; Peter Tyack; Timothy and Janet Williams; Jeffries Wyman
- Lab Books, 3
  Lab books are arranged in numerical order when numbers were shown; otherwise, books are in chronological order with the oldest date first. Oversize files are physically arranged together in a dedicated box.
  Lab Books are handwritten records of scientific observations and experiments and often include machine printouts and photographs showing results of particular tests. In addition to lab books kept as part of routine work at Cornell, Harvard, and Rockefeller Universities, some are for separate projects including the Alpha Helix Expedition and Beebe Tropical Research Station. Some books are titled with brief descriptions of their contents: jamming experiments, underwater sound, bats hitting targets, wind tunnel experiments, human echolocation, ground echolocation, and grid echoes.
  Books kept by laboratory assistants are included and their names are shown when indicated on the book covers. Abbreviated descriptions of contents are shown in the box/folder listing as written on the front of lab books. Some lab books include typewritten summaries of experiments that appear to be drafts for publication. A few have pages inserted with later dates that appear to be reviews of earlier work. Photographs and machine printouts remain with the original lab books in order to preserve valuable context.
  A handwritten note in file shows “Loaned to Nigel V. Woolf Cornell Notebooks 20, 21, 23” and those notebooks are not included in this collection. Numbers 19, 25, and 41-50 are also missing. It is possible that some of the unnumbered ones were intended to have the missing numbers.
  - 1, 1944 December 7-1946 March 23 (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - 2: 1946 March 28-December 26 (added material re bat pulse 1949-50s), 1946 March-December, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - 3, 1946 November-1948 December (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - 4, 1948 December 7-1949 July (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - 5, 1949 July 16-1950 May 3 (Box 16, Folder 156)
  - 6, 1950 May 20-December 5 (Box 17, Folder 157)
  - 7: 1950 June 1-August 29 "Underwater sound, etc." (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - 8: "Bats", 1951 March-July 13 (Box 17, Folder 159)
  - 9: "Bats", 1951 July 20-1952 March 4 (Box 17, Folder 160)
  - 10: "Bats", 1952 March 4-May 15 (Box 18, Folder 161)
  - 11: "Bats", 1952 June 17-August 12 (Box 18, Folder 162)
  - 12, 1952 October 22-1943 March 27 (Box 18, Folder 163)
  - 13: 1953 May 5-June 19 "Bat Flight plus Bat sound records and bird homing obs. Summer '53" (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - 14, 1953 June 19-August 30 (Box 19, Folder 165)
  - 15, 1953 November-1954 June 29 (Box 19, Folder 166)
  - 16: "Bats", 1954 June 30-August 16 (Box 19, Folder 167)
  - 17, 1954 August 23-1955 January 10 (Box 20, Folder 168)
  - 18: "Bats", 1955 June 5-August 14 (Box 20, Folder 169)
  - 22: "Bats - Plecotus and Myotis flight and Jamming Expts", 1957 June 28-November 13 (Box 20, Folder 170)
  - 24: "Bats - Myotis and Eptesicus jamming, Plecotus search for higher frequencies", 1958 June 28-1959 January 7 (Box 20, Folder 171)
  - 26 "J. J. G. McCue and R.E. Richardson", 1959 January 23-December 15 (Box 20, Folder 172)
  - 27: "Bats- Insect catching Webster Lab - Charles R. Michael", 1959 May 28-December 17 (Box 21, Folder 173)
  - 28: "Clarke R. Slater, Animal Orientation-Bats, Myotis jamming and End wall", 1959 June 23-August 29 (Box 21, Folder 174)
  - 29: "Charles Reid Michael - High and Low Frequency Jamming", 1959 July 16-August 24 (Box 21, Folder 175)
  - 30: "Bats, Jamming", 1959 August 28-1960 February 27 (Box 21, Folder 176)
  - 30A: "Bat Flight Data- raw data", 1960 February 1-April 27 (Box 21, Folder 177)
  - 31: "Jamming", 1960 March 9-April 27 (Box 21, Folder 178)
  - 31A: "Plecotus - movies for distance of detection" with later notes, 1960 April 19-May 20 (Box 21, Folder 179)
  - 32: "Plecotus in noise, tabulations, Nancy Griffin's work", 1960 April 26-28 (Box 22, Folder 180)
  - 33, 1960 April 27-July 9 (Box 22, Folder 181)
  - 34: "Noctilio, Simla", 1960 July (Box 22, Folder 182)
  - 35: "Zoological Laboratory, U. of Cambr.", 1960 October-1961 May 15 (Box 22, Folder 183)
  - 36: "Trinidad", 1961 July 10-August 31 (Box 22, Folder 184)
  - 37: 1961 September 21-1962 March 31; "Noctilio 1961 and 1962 Cambridge including XII and inf lar.Sectioning" Simla, 1961-1962 (Box 22, Folder 185)
  - 38 - 1961 June 23-July 31 "Bat tape Catalogue, Dunning; Trinidad Summer 1960; 1961 January 22 England" (Box 23, Folder 186)
  - 39 - 1961 July 31 and 1961 January England "Bat tape Catalogue, Dunning", 1961 January and July 31 (Box 23, Folder 187)
  - "Judith Friend: Disks, Sonar Discrimination Myotis lucifugus", 1962 June 1-August 16 (Box 23, Folder 188)
  - "Judith Friend: Disks, Sonar Discrimination Myotis", 1962 August 17-1963 January (Box 23, Folder 189)
  - "Judith Friend - Preliminary Cylinder expts.", 1964 Spring (Box 23, Folder 190)
  - "Judith Friend: Disk Experiments I, Bat flights tossed and hanging targets", 1964 Spring (Box 23, Folder 191)
  - "Judith Friend: Disk experiments II", 1964 Spring (Box 23, Folder 192)
  - 1964 September and 1966 July-August - "Judith Friend: Last Best Harvard Echo discrimination data", 1964 September, 1966 July-August (Box 23, Folder 193)
  - "M. Flinn: Directional Measurements Book II", 1965 March 13 (Box 24, Folder 194)
  - "Wind tunnel expts.", 1967 May 17-December 13 (Box 24, Folder 195)
  - 52: "Prints of Bat pulses and information concerning them, Record of spectrograms", 1968 April 10-19 (Box 24, Folder 196)
  - AH 1: Alpha Helix, 1969 June-July (Box 24, Folder 197)
  - AH 2: 10 June-21 Dec. 1970 July 1969 Alpha Helix - "New Guinea Bats", 1969 July, 1970 June 10-December 21 (Box 24, Folder 198)
  - 1974 July 12-November 9 (Box 25, Folder 199)
  - GE 1: "Grd. Echos", 1974 November 9-11 (Box 25, Folder 200)
  - GE 2: "Grd. Echos", 1974 November 9-11 (Box 25, Folder 201)
  - H.E. 1, 1975 November 18-1981 January 31 (Box 25, Folder 202)
  - "Human Echolocation Test Sheets", 1980 January-March (Box 25, Folder 203)
  - 1975 May - "Pulse and Echoes" and 1980 Spring - "Human Echolocation duplicate prints and negatives", 1975 May, 1980 Spring (Box 25, Folder 204)
  - 40: 1961 June 23 -"Bat Movie Film Catalogue, - Dunning" "Trinidad - Summer 1960; England 1960-1961" (Box 26, Folder 205)
  - Simla, Trinidad, 1966 June 13-Aug 1966 (Box 26, Folder 206)
  - 51, 1967 October 10-1968 March 29 (Box 26, Folder 207)
  - Ground Echoes, 1974 November 2-16 (Box 26, Folder 208)
- Publications, 4
  Series 4 includes newspaper and magazine clippings as well as scientific reprints and other publications by Griffin and fellow scientists. The Newspaper and Magazine articles folder has an article about Theodore Hammel who worked on the atom bomb in Los Alamos, MN and subsequently changed his graduate studies from physics to physiology as a result of hearing a lecture by Griffin. Newspaper and magazine articles address various aspects of Griffin’s work for a general public audience—bat “radar,” animal communication, bat diseases, “bat bomb.” Some have interviews with Griffin, his students, or fellow scientists. A few are clippings of bats in advertisements or comic strips and some articles are in German and Spanish language publications.
  A list of Griffin’s publications through 1988 is at the front of the first folder of “Articles, Reprints, Reviews-by Griffin.”
  This collection does not contain a complete set of all of his publications.
  Newspaper and Magazine Clippings are arranged in chronological order with newest date first. Items with no date are at the end of the folder. Publications by Griffin as author or co-author are in chronological order with newest date first. Publications by others are in alphabetical order by surname of first author.
  - Newspaper and Magazine Articles (Box 26, Folder 209)
  - Griffin, Animal Thinking (Box 27, Folder 210)
    Animal Thinking, Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 1984.
  - Griffin, The Question of Animal Awareness (First and Second edition.) (Box 27, Folder 211)
    The Question of Animal Awareness: Evolutionary Continuity of Mental Experience, New York: Rockefeller University Press, 1976.
  - Griffin and Novick, Animal Structure and Function; Scientific American-Animal Engineering (Box 27, Folder 212)
    Introduction and "More About Bat 'Radar'" in Readings from Scientific American: Animal Engineering, San Francisco: W. H. Freeman and Co., 1974. Animal Structure and Function, New York: Holt, Rinehart, and Winston Inc., 1970.
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Griffin, 1980s (Box 27, Folder 213)
    "Cognitive Aspects of Echolocation" in Animal Sonar, Processes and Performance, New York: Plenum, 1988. Review of Tactical Deception in Primates, Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 11:233-273, 1988. "Foreword to papers on Magnetic Sensitivity in Birds" in Animal Learning and Behavior,, 1987. Review of The Comparative Psychology of Intelligence, Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 10:645-695, 1987. Foreword in Dolphin Cognition and Behavior: A Comparative Approach, Hillsdale, NJ: L. Erlbaum Assoc., 1986. "Epilogue: The Cognitive Dimensions of Animal Communication" in Experimental Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology, New York: Springer, 1985. "Recollections of an Experimental Naturalist" in Leaders in the Study of Animal Behavior, Lewisburg, PA: Bucknell University Press, 1985. Animal Consciousness, Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews, 9: 615-622, 1985. Animal Thinking, excerpts, American Scientist, 72:456-464, 1984. Introduction to Animal Mind - Human Mind, Dahlem Workshop Report, Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 1982. Ecology of Migration: Is Magnetic Orientation a Reality?, Quarterly Review of Biology, Vol. 57, No. 3, 1982. High altitude echolocation of Insects by Bats, Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology, 10:303-306, 1982. Echolocation by Cave Swiftlets, Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology, 10:119-123, 1982. The Question of Animal Awareness: Evolutionary Continuity of Mental Experience, Los Altos, CA: William Kaufman, Inc., 1981. The Early History of Research on Echolocation in Animal Sonar Systems, New York: Plenum, 1980.
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Griffin, 1970s (Box 27, Folder 214)
    Radar Observations of Bird Migration over the Western North Atlantic Ocean, Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology, 4:225-264, 1979. Echolocation of Extended Surfaces in Animal Migration, Navigation, and Homing, New York: Academic Press, 1978. The Sensory Physiology of Animal Orientation in Harvey Lectures (Series 71), New York: Academic Press, 1978. Expanding Horizons in Animal Communications Behavior in How Animals Communicate, Bloomington, IN: Indiana University Press, 1977. Echolocation and its Relevance to Communication Behavior in How Animals Communicate, Bloomington, IN: Indiana University Press, 1977. The Audibility of Frog Choruses to Migrating Birds, Animal Behaviour, 24:421-427, 1976. Reactions of Migrating Birds to Lights and Aircraft, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 1976. Sounds Audible to Migrating Birds, Animal Behaviour, 22:672-678, 1974. Echolocation of Insects by Horseshoe Bats, Nature, Vol. 250, No. 5469, pp. 731-732, 1974. Echolocation in Basic Mechanisms in Hearing, New York: Academic Press, 1973. Oriented Bird Migration In or Between Opaque Cloud Layers, Proceedings, American Philosophical Society, Vol. 117, No. 2, pp. 117-141, 1973. Nocturnal Bird Migration in Opaque Clouds in Animal Orientation and Navigation, Washington, D.C.: U. S. Government Printing Office, 1972. The Importance of Atmospheric Attenuation for the Echolocation of Bats (Chiropetera), Animal Behaviour, 19:55-61, 1971. Sensitivity of Echolocation in Cave Swiftlets, The Biological Bulletin, 139:495-501, 1970. Migrations and Homing of Bats, in Biology of Bats, Vol. 1, New York: Academic Press, 1970.
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Griffin, 1960s (Box 28, Folder 215)
    The Physiology and Geophysics of Bird Navigation, Quarterly Review of Biology, 44:255-276, 1969. Echo-Orientierung und Fledermausflug, Naturwissenschaft und Medizin, Vol. 27, No. 3, 1969. Echolocation and its Relevance to Communication Behavior in Animal Communication, Bloomington, IN: Indiana University Press, 1968. The Homing Ability of the Neotropical Bat Phyllostomus Hastatus, with Evidence for Visual Orientation, Animal Behaviour, Vol. 14, No. 4, pp. 468-473, 1966. Discriminative Echolocation by Bats, Animal Sonar Systems, 1966. Bird Migration and Celestial Navigation, Rockefeller University Review, Vol. 3, No. 4, 1965. Target Discrimination by the Echolocation of Bats, Journal of Experimental Zoology, Vol. 158, No. 2, pp. 155-168, 1965. Target Discrimination by the Echolocation of Bats, unknown, 1965. Probable 24-year Longevity records for Myotis Lucifugus, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 46, No. 2, 1965. Die fischenden Fladermause von Trinidad, Das Tier, 1964. The Fishing Bats of Trinidad, Animal Kingdom, Vol. 66, No. 5, 1963. Animal Navigation, Proceedings, International Congress of Zoology, Vol. 4, 1963. The Potential for Telemetry in Studies of Animal Orientation at Bio-Telemetry Conference, Oxford: Pergamon Press, 1963. Comparative Studies of the Orientation Sounds of Bats, Symposium, Zoological Society of London, No. 7, pp. 61-72, 1962. The Role of the Flight Membranes in Insect Capture by Bats, Animal Behaviour, 10:3-4, 1962. Neural Discriminations Achieved by Bats in Echolocation, Science, 1962. Ultrasonic Frequencies in Bird Song, Ibis, 104:220-227, 1961. Laryngeal Mechanisms in Bats for the Production of Orientation Sounds, Journal of Experimental Zoology, Vol. 148, No. 2, pp. 125-146, 1961. Notes on Homing and Migratory Behavior of Bats, Ecology, Vol. 41, No. 2, 1960. The Echolocation of Flying Insects by Bats, Animal Behaviour, 8:141-154, 1960.
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Griffin, 1950s (Box 28, Folder 216)
    The Sensitivity of Echolocation in the Fruit Bat, Rousettus, Biological Bulletin, Vol. 115, No. 1, pp. 107-113, 1958. More About Bat "Radar", Scientific American, Vol. 199, No. 1, 1958. The Sensitivity of Echolocation in Bats, Biological Bulletin, Vol. 114, No. 1, pp. 10-22, 1958. The Ultrasonic 'Radar' of the Bat, The Reflector, Vol. 6, No. 5, 1958. Ability of Bats to Discriminate Echoes from Louder Noise, Science, Vol. 128, No. 3316, pp. 145-147, 1958. Longevity Records and Notes on Tooth Wear of Bats, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 38, No. 3, 1957. Further Observations of Homing Terns, Biological Bulletin, Vol. 111, No. 2, pp. 235-239, 1956. Acoustic Orientation of Neotropical Bats, Journal of Experimental Zoology, Vol. 130, No. 2, pp. 251-300, 1955. Initial Flight Directions of Homing Birds, Biological Bulletin, Vol. 108, No. 3, pp. 264-276, 1955. An Echo-Sounding Bird, Discovery, Vol. 16, No. 3, 1955. Hearing and Acoustic Orientation in Marine Animals in Marine Biology and Oceanography, London: Pergamon Press, Ltd., pp. 406-417, 1955. Review of Avian Physiology, Science Monthly, 1954. Bird Sonar, Scientific American, Vol. 190, No. 3, 1954. Deluge Underground, The American Caver, Vol. 15, 1953. Acoustic Orientation in the Oil Bird Steatornis, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 39, No. 8, pp. 884-893, 1953. Sensory Physiology and the Orientation of Animals, American Scientist, Vol. 41, No. 2, 1953. Bat Sounds Under Natural Conditions, with Evidence for Echolocation of Insect Prey, Journal of Experimental Zoology, Vol. 123, No. 3, pp. 435-466, 1953. Airplane Observations of Homing Birds, Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology, Vol. 107, No. 8, 1952. Bird Navigation, Feathers, Vol. 14, No. 9, 1952. Bird Navigation, Biological Reviews, Vol. 27, 1952. Radioactive Tagging of Animals Under Natural Conditions, Ecology, vol. 33, No. 3, 1952. Acoustic Location of Insect Prey by Bats, The Anatomical Record, Vol. 111, No. 3, 1951. Alaskan Bird Migrations, Research Reviews, 1951. Audible and Ultrasonic Sounds of Bats, Experientia, Vol. 7, 1951. Measurements of the Ultrasonic Cries of Bats, The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, Vol. 22, No. 2, pp. 247-255, 1950. The Navigation of Bats, Scientific American, Vol. 183, No. 2, 1950.
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Griffin, 1940s (Box 28, Folder 217)
    Die Navigation der Vogel, Naturwissenschaftliche Rundschau, 1949. Airplane Observations of Homing Birds, Ecology, Vol. 30, No. 2, 1949. The Navigation of Birds, Scientific American, 1948. Experiments on Bird Navigation, Science, Vol. 107, No. 2779, pp. 347-349, 1948. The Sensitivity of the Human Eye to Infra- Red Radiation, Journal of the Optical Society of America, Vol. 37, No. 7, pp. 546-554, 1947. The Change in Refractive Power of the Human Eye in Dim and Bright Light, Journal of the Optical Society of America, Vol. 37, No. 5, pp. 321-336, 1947. Supersonic Cries of Bats, Nature, Vol. 158, pp. 46-48, 1946. The Effects of Cold and rate of Ascent on Aero-Embolism, Aviation Medicine, 1946. Travels of Banded Cave Bats, Journal of Mammalogy, vol. 26, No. 1, pp. 15-23, 1945. Echolocation by Blind Men, Bats and Radar, Science, Vol. 100, No. 2609, pp. 589-590, 1944. How Bats Guide Their Flight by Supersonic Echoes, American Journal of Physics, Vol. 12, No. 6, pp. 342-345, 1944. The Sensory Basis of Bird Navigation, The Quarterly Review of Biology, Vol. 19, No. 1, pp. 15-31, 1944. Homing Experiments with Herring Gulls and Common Terns, Bird Banding, Vol. 14, No. 1 and 2, 1943. Obstacle avoidance by Flying Bats: The cries of Bats, Journal of Experimental Zoology, Vol. 89, No. 3, 1942. Flying Ornithologists, Bulletin of Massachusetts Audubon Society, Vol. 26, No. 3, pp. 55-60, 1942. The Sensory basis of Obstacle Avoidance by Flying Bats, Journal of Experimental Zoology, Vol. 86, No. 3, 1941. Notes on the Life Histories of New England Cave Bats, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 21, No. 2, pp. 181-187, 1940. Homing Experiments with Leach's Petrels, The Auk, Vol. 57, pp. 61-74, 1940. Migrations of New England Bats, Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoology, Vol. 86, No. 6, 1940.
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Griffin, 1930s (Box 28, Folder 218)
    Bats Migrate Too, New England Naturalist, No. 5, 1939. Wings Without Feathers, New England Naturalist, No. 4, 1939. Mother Cary's Chickens, Bulletin of Massachusetts Audubon Society, Vol. 23, No. 3, 1939. Experimental Determinations of Supersonic Notes Emitted by Bats, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 19, No. 4, pp. 454-455, 1938. Activity Rhythms in Bats Under Constant External Conditions, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 18, No. 3, pp. 337-338, 1937. Bat Banding, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 17, No. 3, pp. 235-239, 1936. Stomach Contents of Atlantic Harbor Seals, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 17, No. 1, pp. 65-66, 1936. Marking Bats, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 15, No. 3, pp. 202-207, 1934. Migratory Behavior in Encyclopedia of Science and Technology, New York: McGraw Hill, undated Bat in, Encyclopedia, unknown, undated
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Others - A-G (Box 29, Folder 219)
    Barbour, Thomas, Bats, The Atlantic, 1945. Bentley, David R., Genetic Control of an Insect Neuronal Network, Science, Vol. 174, pp. 1139-1141, 1971. Boyden, Louise, Bats on the Beam: Nature's 'Built-in' Equipment controls Blind Flying by Supersonic Broadcasting, Scientific American, Vol. 165, No. 2, pp. 78-79, 1941. Bradley, James V., Effect of Gloves on Control Operation Time, Washington, D.C.: U.S. Air Force, 1956. Brines, Michael L. and James L. Gould, Bees have Rules, Science, Vol. 206, pp.571-573, 1979. Burton, Maurice, Checkered Distribution of Bats, Illustrated London News, 1962. Carson, Rachel, The Bat Knew It First, Collier's Weekly, 1944. Constantine, Denny G., Jens A. Jenson and Ernest S. Tierkel, The Use of Radiolabeling in Determining Prey-Predator Relationships, Journal of Mammalogy, Vol. 40, No. 2,pp. 240-242, 1959. Dresner, Simon, Sound Beyond Hearing, Science Teacher's World, 1961. Emsley, Michael G., David A. Nickle, and W. Wayne Moss, The Value of the Stridulatory File and Other Characters in Tettioniid Taxonomy (Orthoptera), Notulae Naturae, No. 404, 1967. Fisher, Arthur, Animals that "SEE" with Their Ears, Science Teacher's World, 1961. Flowers, Betty, Bird Migration, Highlights, 1968. Galambos, Robert, Flight in the Dark: A Study of Bats, Scientific Monthly, Vol. 56, No. 2, 1943. Gallant, Roy A., How Bats "see" by Sound, Science World, Vol. 4, No. 5, 1958. Gomez, Ramon Mudarra, La Cueva del Guacharo, El Agricultor Venezolano, Vol. 13, No. 138, 1950. Grew, E.S., The Radar of the Bat, Illustrated London News, 1946.
  - Articles, Reprints, Reviews by Others - H-Z (Box 29, Folder 220)
    Hapgood, Fred, The Ghostly Wings of Night, GEO: The Earth Diary, Vol. 3, 1981. Harris, David M. and Peter Dallos, Forward Masking of Auditory Nerve Fiber Responses, Journal of Neurophysiology, Vol. 42, No. 4, 1979. Harvey, Andre, The Bat-Navigator First Class, Science World: Scholastic Teacher, Vol. 13, No. 3, 1966. Kettering, C. F., Catching Up With Nature, General Motors Symphony of the Air, 1944. Markl, Hubert, Stridulation in Leaf-Cutting Ants, Science, Vol. 149, No. 3690, 1965. Michener, Martin C. and Charles Walcott, Navigation of Single Homing Pigeons: Airplane Observations by Radio Tracking, Science, Vol. 154, No. 3748, pp. 410-413, 1966. Olson, Hank, W6GXN, and John Van Geen, The FVGT Box, QST, 1972. Pennington, Jim, Bats and Radar, Princeton Engineer, 1955. Poling, James, The Baffling BAT, National Wildlife, undated. Pringle, Laurence, Hunting with Echoes, Nature and Science, Vol. 4, No. 3, 1966. Redfield, Alfred C., Tide and Time on Cape Cod, The Cape Cod Naturalist, Vol. 1, No. 2, pp. 22-26, 1972. Safford, Edward L., Jr., Modern Radar: Theory, Operation and Maintenance, Blue Ridge Summit, PA: Tab Books, Inc., undated. Schnitzler, Hans-Ulrich, Echoortung bei der Fledermaus Chilonycteris rubiginosa, Z. vergl. Physiologie, Vol. 68, pp. 25-38, 1970. Solomon, Joan, Bats, The Sciences, Vol. 10, No. 3, 1970. Steen, J. and P. S. Enger, Muscular Heat Production in Pigeons During Exposure to Cold, The American Journal of Physiology, Vol. 191, No. 1, 1957. Steen, Jon, Climatic Adaptation in Some Small Northern Birds, Ecology, Vol. 39, No. 4, 1958. Suthers, Roderick A., Wie orten fischfangende Flederm„use ihre Beute?, UMSCHAU, 1967. Teale, Edwin, How Bats "See" in the Dark, Popular Science, 1941. White, E. B., Song of the Queen Bee, n. p., undated. Zuloaga, Guillermo, Los gu charos se gu¡an por Radar en la oscuridad, El Farol, No. 147, 1953.
  - Publications - By Others (Waring) (Box 29, Folder 221)